#哈喽大家好
Hello everyone
#这两三年大家一直在问我们厨房里面用的是什么菜板
In the last few years, people keep asking us what kind of cutting board we use
#今天就跟大家分享一下
Today we will share that with everyone
#我们厨房里面是用的这种松木
We use this type of pine wood in the kitchen
#这个木头其实很适合商用
This wood is very appropriate for business use
#四伯爷家里面没得好适合用这个
Uncle do you have one like this
#在我们农村不适合
It's not really useful for our village
#我们农村的厨房太窄 用这么大的菜墩不适宜
Our village kitchens are too small, to use such a large cutting board wouldn't be appropriate
#对 我们这个菜板它的厚度有10多公分（厚）的有20公分（厚）的
Yes, our cutting boards range from 10cm to 20cm thick
#但是它这个重量是非常重的
However it is also very heavy
#这个我估计是40斤这个大概有60斤
This one is roughly 40 jin, the large one probably 60 jin (jin = 500g)
#所以就不是很适合家里面用
So it wouldn't really fit in a family home.
#还有一个就是这个的话长时间不用
One more thing, is that if it is not used for a while
#我说的长时间是1天2天不用
What I mean by a while is 1-2 days
#它就会发霉
It'll grow mold
# 看到了嘛这个青色的就是发了霉的
Look, these green parts are mold
#还有再一个就是容易开裂有裂痕
It also splits easily, look at the split
#这样子就能看到这个地方
Look at this spot
#所以这个菜板大家看起来是很好看的
So this cutting board at first appears to be very glamorous
#这一面你看又大花纹又好
On this side, large surface, beautiful etching
#但是非常不适合家用
But it is unfit for home use
#因为你试想一下有哪个
Because if you think about it
#家庭妇女能抱得动60斤的砧板放来放去的是吧
How many housewives can repeatedly shuffle around a 60 jin cutting board
#还有一个就是要长时间用
Also it needs to be used a lot
#使用次数要增加
As in usage count must be high
#比如说一天到晚都在用
Such as from sunrise to sunset
#它就没有那么容易发这种霉
To prevent it from growing mold
#如果你是一日做三餐饭菜的话
If you only make 3 meals a day
#你其中停了一天第二天它就会发这种霉
When you stop, by the 2nd day it will have grown mold
#所以机动性不强实用性不高
So the utility is not very high
#但是说在我们专业厨房里面就是实用
But for the professional kitchen it is very appropriate
#这个菜板的花纹很好看
The etchings are very pretty
#圆的
Round
#嗯 那个花纹有点好看
Yeah, the etching is quite pretty
#像靶心一样
Like the bullseye of dartboard
#这种菜板在四川基本上很难买
It's hard to purchase this type of cutting board in Sichuan
#我买这2个菜板从广东买回来
I bought both of these from Guangdong
#买才花了不到200块运费就花了200多
The boards only cost 200 rmb, but shipping was another 200.
#好 下面我来跟大家分享菜板该怎么样去保养
Ok, next we'll share with everyone on how to take care of your cutting board
#四伯爷有没有盐巴得哦
Uncle, do you have some salt
#有
Yeah
#来嘛 我抱这个轻点的嘛
Come, I'll carry the lighter one
#抱来放这里就是
Bring it over and put it over here
#放这里
Put it over here
#年纪大点抱轻点的
The elderly should carry lighter ones
#年纪小的就抱重点的
The younger ones can carry the heavier ones
#哎呀 老子抱不起了
Aiya, I can't hold it anymore
#我来我来
Let me
#好重哦
So heavy
#不关事不关事 没得事
It's okay, no problem
#好 现在我们准备下一步
Ok let's prepare for the next step
#这两个菜墩就是放在这个盆里面
We'll leave both cutting boards in the basins
#下一步加盐进去 加盐水泡
The next step is to add salt, and soak in the saltwater
#泡个2-3天吧
Soak for about 2-3 days
#我去拿盐巴来
I'll go get the salt
#这个菜板啊 有这么大
This cutting board, to be this big
#起码都是那个原始森林里的树子才有这么粗来锯的
It was probably sawed down from one of the first trees in the forest
#好了我现在把我们家里面所有的盐都拿过来了
Ok I've brought over all of the salt that we have in the house
#全部倒进去
Toss it all in
#这个比腌腊肉都还来火哦
This is even crazier than that time we made cured meats
#嘿嘿
Hehe
#好 可以了
Ok, done
#现在我们这个盐倒在这里面再加水把它泡住
Now we'll dump the salt in, and add water to soak
#加盐进去的话就是起一个杀菌（效果）
Adding salt will create an anti-microbial environment
#还有一个就是把它表面这个霉菌给它去一去
And also remove some of the surface mold
#泡个几天呢要
Soak for how many days?
#泡它2天嘛
Soak for about 2 days
#泡2-3天都可以
We can let it soak 2-3 days
#嗯 可以
Yeah that'd be fine
#呐 都在抢水了
It's absorbing the water
#起泡了
It's bubbling
#是不是哦
Right?
#是啊
Yeah
#在抢水噶
It's absorbing the water
#你看我们这个菜板它现在在冒泡
You see the cutting board making bubbles?
#在冒泡儿咯
It's bubbling
#多搅几下 把这个盐搅化
Mix it a bit, let the salt dissolve
#好了 （到）今天我们这个菜板已经泡了3天了
Ok, as of today the cutting boards have been soaked for 3 days
#现在我来把它捞出来把它晾一下
Now we'll take them out and dry them
#晾完之后就还剩最后一步
Once dried we'll move to the final step
#这个泡了水的菜板我估计有七八十斤
I estimate that the soaked cutting board weighs 70-80 jin
#好了 再晾个几个小时
Ok, let it dry for a few more hours
#这个菜板我们已经泡了三天了
We've soaked the cutting board for 3 days already
#现在我把它拿起来晾了几个小时快要晾干了
Now we've taken it out to dry for a few hours, and it's almost fully dry
#现在我就准备把它进行下一步
Now we'll prepare it for the next step
#但是下一步之前我教你们认一下这个菜板
But before that step, I'll teach you how to recognize a cutting board
#你看 这个圈数越多的话就说明这个菜板的质量就越硬
Look, the more rings it has, the harder the cutting board
#然后切什么剁什么就不会说把这个剁烂剁伤
So when you are chopping, it won't damage the cutting board
#我们再看一下这个
Let's look at this one
#这个的话它圈圈就比较少
This one has fewer rings
#比较少的话就说明这个就要比这个要软一点
Fewer rings means it'll be softer
#这个圈圈少的话就说明这个
This one has fewer rings meaning
它年生（树龄）就要短点撒
The age of the tree is younger
#年龄没得这个大
Not as old as this one
#这个菜板的年纪大概是70岁 70年
This cutting board is probably 70 years old, 70 years
#这个我估计只有30多年吧
This one I'm estimating 30 years ish.
#我没数 大概是30多年
I didn't count, probably 30 ish.
#因为这个有70多圈
Because this one has around 70 rings
#要得 这哈子四伯爷帮我烧哈火嘛 我烧点（熟）油
Alright, Uncle can you start a fire for me, I'll heat up some oil
#现在我来烧点火 伯爷帮我烧火
I'll light the fire, my Uncle will stoke it.
#我拿这个油倒进去把它烧热
I'll pour the oil in to heat it up
#烧热了之后淋在这个菜板上面
Once it's hot, I'll drizzle it on the cutting board
#这个就根据你们自己条件来了
So do this step according to your own conditions
#因为我这里是两个砧板 我估计要倒个两斤
Because I have 2 cutting boards, so I'll probably need 2 jin
#这个油烧到它七八成 烧到200度左右
We want it to be heated to about 200C
#目的就是先把这个油灭一下菌
The goal is to kill some microbes
#好了 我们这个油差不多可以了
Ok, the oil is just about done
#把它端下来放在地下慢慢泼
Move it to the ground and we'll slowly drizzle it
#要冷哦放在地下
It will become cold if you leave it on the ground
#不怕得
It's fine
#我们这个油烧烫一点 给它这样泼上去
Our oil is very hot, pour it on like this
#这个就是宽油菜板
This is a Kuan You (literally "broad oil") cutting board
#这样子保养一下的话它就不会发霉
This will protect it and prevent mold
#用这个刷子把它刷均匀一点
Now use a brush to spread it out evenly
#好啦 我们这个就差不多了
Ok that's about it
#把它刷均匀了就差不多了
Brush it evenly and that's about it
#剩下的油的话可以以后洗完砧板之后再用它烧热了这样子淋上去
If there's leftover oil, in the future you can heat it up and use it to coat the cutting board after rinsing like so
#多保养几次
Do the seasoning step a few more times
#这个（用）油保养了之后千万不要用洗洁精去洗
Once you've used oil to season the board, don't use detergent to clean it
#可以用热水把它洗一下
Just use hot water to rinse
#如果你用了洗洁精去洗的话这个油相当于浪费了
If you use detergent, then you've wasted all of the oil
#就没有保养到位
And will have removed the seasoning
#好啦 本期视频就到这里了
Ok, the video ends here.
#拜拜
Bye bye